PETER LITTLE

Full-Stack Web Developer

CONTACT



Toronto, ON Canada



thepeterlittle@gmail.com



(289) 404 - 6620



PeterLittleDev

EDUCATION

BACHLOR OF ENGINEERING: SOFTWARE (2012 - 2016)

Ontario Tech University

Graduated with honours (3.69 GPA) while receiving multiple Dean's & President's List awards.

PROFILE

Hi! I'm Peter, a team-oriented and hardworking full-stack web developer, with over 8 years of experience. I'm looking for the next challenge in my career.

I'm extremely passionate about two things: selfimprovement, and building great things so, I'm most interested in a great company where I can do both. A company that I can really sink my teeth into, make a big impact and grow along the way.

I would love the opportunity to discuss potential positions in your company and how I could be a fantastic addition to your team.

HOBBIES











EXPERIENCE

SENIOR FULL STACK DEVELOPER (Contract)

Aug 2023 - Nov 2023

GovernGPT.ai | Toronto, Ontario

Responsible for working directly with the CTO and CEO to rapidly prototype various incarnations of the product during the early stages of this Y-Combinator Startup (W24)

This included research, design, development, testing, and maintenance in javascript, python, and prompt engineering

CTO & CO-FOUNDER

Mar 2022 - April 2023

StartScreen.io | Toronto, Ontario

Within the Entrepreneur First Talent Accelerator (TO3), My co-founder and I created our company and received funding offers from various investors.

As Co-Founder and CTO I was responsible for the entire development lifecycle of our products, along with several non-technical responsibilities including Customer Discovery/development, pitching, investor relations, and management of the company.

SENIOR FULL-STACK DEVELOPER

Oct 2020 - Mar 2022

CrowdRiff.com | Toronto, Ontario

As a senior dev it was my responsibility to lead a team of developers to the end-to-end completion of various features on our core product. With sole ownership over these projects, it was my responsibility to manage all aspects of the project. This included running all required meetings, research, planning, grooming, testing, implementation, and helping team members

MODEL & ACTOR / FREELANCE DEVELOPER

2019 - 2020

ICON Models / Freelance | Toronto, Ontario

In April 2019 I was scouted and signed by a top modeling and acting agency in Toronto. While working as a model I decided it was the perfect opportunity to do freelance development and work every day on my own projects.

Please see page 2 for overview of some of my side-projects.

FULL-STACK DEVELOPER / TEAM LEAD

2016 - 2019

360Insights | Whitby, Ontario

Starting out as a junior developer, throughout my 3 years at 360 my role continuously grew until I was selected to take over for an outgoing team lead

As acting team lead, I was responsible for facilitating technical discussions, interviewing and onboarding new members, as well as representing my team in cross-team collaborations and meetings with management.

My other responsibilities included: designing and implementing various features across both the front-end and back-end of our platform.

SOFTWARE ENGINEERING RESEARCH TECHNICIAN

Summer 2015

University of Ontario Institute of Technology

Responsible for the complete development of a Windows app including design, implementation, and testing. -- See GameLink (pg.2)

(some of my) Projects

CareerMapper.ai | Ai Enabled Web App

CareerMapper.ai uses ai to design a learning path for users to follow to reach their dream job an.

- Next.js Open.ai Vercel
- Tailwind Supabase
- Mixpanel

Stealth Onboarding Startup | Ai Enabled Web App

An app that allowed early-stage startups to leverage ai to read their knowledge base and automatically create onboarding material for new hires.

- Next.js Open.ai
- LangChain Tailwind
- Promptmetheus
- Supabase Mixpanel

Savvy Price Tracker | Chrome Extension

Savvy is a Chrome extension that uses crowdsourced data to allow users to automatically track the prices of products on they see while shopping online.

- React.jsWebpack
- Node.jsExpress
- GraphQL Mongo DB
- AWS (EBS / Lambda)

LandOfRhythmos.com | Website (Freelance)

Developed for a freelance client, Rhythmos is a children's musical edutainment company. I was tasked with creating a site that displayed the creativity and playfulness of the brand.

- Javascript HTML
- CSS(SASS) Gulp
- BootstrapPHP

MensFashion.ai | Cloud-based Instagram Bot

A men's fashion Instagram account run by a cloud-based bot. The bot periodically scrapes Instagram for the best new posts and then automatically re-posts them at scheduled times. Includes an admin UI for monitoring.

- Node.js Puppeteer
- Google Cloud Platform
- Mongo DB React

OutfitFinds.com | Web Application

Outfitfinds.com is a fashion site for Pinterest-esk fashion browsing. Users can browse outfits, discover where to find the pieces of the outfit and shop for matching accessories using the built-in Shopify drop-shipping store.

- Gatsby.jsNetlify
- Liquid(Shopify) React
- Puppeteer GraphQL
- CSS in JS

TopTorial.io | Web Application

Toptorial.io is a universal web app designed to allow users to browse and search for top-rated programming books for various languages.

- Node.js React Redux
- Next.js Heroku Redis
- Sketch Mongo DB

GameLink | Windows Application

Gamelink is a platform for creating, facilitating, and grading of algorithm-based coding competitions for the faculty of Software Engineering at UOIT.

- Java JUnit Maven
- WebSockets
 UML